Found 122 candidate chunks

--- en_wikipedia_org_salem_s_lot_1979_miniseries_salems_lot_1979_0002 | SALEMS_LOT_1979 ---
After a large crate is delivered to the Marsten House one night, townspeople begin to disappear or die under strange circumstances. Mears and Straker are the main suspects as they are both new in town, but it eventually becomes clear that the crate contained Straker's business partner, Kurt Barlowùan ancient vampire who has come to Salem's Lot after sending his servant Straker to prepare for his a

--- en_wikipedia_org_salem_s_lot_1979_miniseries_salems_lot_1979_0004 | SALEMS_LOT_1979 ---
After Warner Bros. acquired the rights to 'Salem's Lot, the studio sought to turn the 400+page novel by Stephen King into a feature film, while still remaining faithful to the source material. Producer Stirling Silliphant, screenwriter Robert Getchell, and writer/director Larry Cohen all contributed screenplays but none proved satisfactory. "It was a mess," King said. "Every director in Hollywood 

--- en_wikipedia_org_salem_s_lot_1979_miniseries_salems_lot_1979_0005 | SALEMS_LOT_1979 ---
Although the miniseries follows the general outline of King's novel, there are a few substantial deviations for creative or logistical reasons. Many characters have been combined or merely deleted, as have certain subplots, and the character of Barlow is vastly different in the miniseries from how he is in the novel. However, Stephen King praised Paul Monash's screenplay and stated "Monash has suc

--- en_wikipedia_org_salem_s_lot_1979_miniseries_salems_lot_1979_0006 | SALEMS_LOT_1979 ---
We went back to the old German Nosferatu concept where he is the essence of evil, and not anything romantic or smarmy, or, you know, the rouge-cheeked, widow-peaked Dracula. I wanted nothing suave or sexual, because I just didn't think it'd work; we've seen too much of it. The other thing we did with the character which I think is an improvement is that Barlow does not speak. When he's killed at t

--- en_wikipedia_org_salem_s_lot_1979_miniseries_salems_lot_1979_0007 | SALEMS_LOT_1979 ---
Other changes by Kobritz included having the final confrontation with Barlow in the cellar of the Marsten House whereas in the book it is in the basement of Eva Miller's boarding house, a concept Kobritz felt "Just doesn't work. I mean, from a point of sheer construction in a well-written screenplay, he's got to reside in the inside of the Marsten House. He's a major star in the picture û the thir

--- en_wikipedia_org_salem_s_lot_1979_miniseries_salems_lot_1979_0008 | SALEMS_LOT_1979 ---
Salem's Lot does not rely on the same kind of dynamics as The Texas Chain Saw Massacre. "This film is very spooky û it suggests things and always has the overtone of the grave. It affects you differently than my other horror films. It's more soft-shelled," director Tobe Hooper explains. "A television movie does not have blood or violence. It has atmosphere which creates something you cannot escape

--- en_wikipedia_org_salem_s_lot_1979_miniseries_salems_lot_1979_0009 | SALEMS_LOT_1979 ---
Unable to find a house in Ferndale that resembled the Marsten House from the book, an estimated $100,000 was spent on constructing a three-story facade over an existing house on a hillside, overlooking Ferndale and the Eel River Valley. Designed by Mort Rabinowitz, it took 20 days to build. Another $70,000 was spent on constructing the interior set of the house which proved even more difficult for

--- en_wikipedia_org_salem_s_lot_1979_miniseries_salems_lot_1979_0012 | SALEMS_LOT_1979 ---
Filmmaker Mike Flanagan's 2021 horror limited series Midnight Mass is inspired by both the novel and the miniseries. Like Salem's Lot, Midnight Mass centers around a small town where a former local returns after an extended period of time. The arrival of a strange new resident (in King's story, Straker, in Flanagan's series the substitute priest), and the revelation of the town being infected by v

--- en_wikipedia_org_salem_s_lot_2004_miniseries_salems_lot_2004_0002 | SALEMS_LOT_2004 ---
Susan and schoolboy Mark Petrie are captured by Straker when they break into the Marsten house. Mark escapes, but Susan is taken to the cellar to meet Barlow. Ben, Mark, Callahan and Cody act as vampire hunters. In the Marsten house, they find Straker's body drained of blood. They destroy the vampires in the cellar, but Ben discovers Susan has been turned. Instead of destroying her, Ben intends to

--- en_wikipedia_org_salem_s_lot_film_salems_lot_2024_0007 | SALEMS_LOT_2024 ---
However, by October 2023, Warner Bros. Pictures was considering releasing the film on Max due to the 2023 SAG-AFTRA strike creating a "growing need for Max content", although a spokesperson stated no decision regarding the film's future distribution plans had been made yet.[27] In February 2024, King questioned why there were still no confirmed release plans for the film, stating that he is "not s

--- en_wikipedia_org_salem_s_lot_salems_lot_novel_0005 | SALEMS_LOT_NOVEL ---
King expands on this thought of the 20th-century vampire in his essay for Adeline Magazine, "On Becoming a Brand Name" (February 1980): "I began to turn the idea over in my mind, and it began to coalesce into a possible novel. I thought it would make a good one, if I could create a fictional town with enough prosaic reality about it to offset the comic-book menace of a bunch of vampires." Yet the 

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_film_shining_kubrick_0006 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
The actresses who played the ghosts of the murdered Grady daughters, Lisa and Louise Burns, are identical twins.[11] The characters in the book and film script are sisters, but not twins. In the film's dialogue, Ullman says that he thinks that they were "about eight and ten". Nonetheless, they are frequently referred to in discussions about the film as "the Grady twins".
There is a resemblance in 

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_film_shining_kubrick_0008 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
Several critics have also interpreted The Shining less as a conventional ghost story than as a work about family violence, patriarchal authority, and the collapse of masculine identity. In Feminist Studies, Elizabeth Jean Hornbeck argues that, despite its Gothic and supernatural elements, the film is "at its core, a story about domestic violence", with Jack Torrance functioning as a predatory fath

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_film_shining_kubrick_0013 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
Geoffrey Cocks notes that the film contains many allusions to fairy-tales, both Hansel and Gretel and The Three Little Pigs,[26] with Jack Torrance identified as the Big Bad Wolf, which Bruno Bettelheim interprets as standing for "all the asocial unconscious devouring powers" that must be overcome by a child's ego.
The saying "all work and no play makes Jack a dull boy" appeared first in James How

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_film_shining_kubrick_0014 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
Many of the paintings that appear include depictions of Canada or are painted by Canadian artists including Le Campement du Trappeur (1931) by Clarence Gagnon, December Afternoon (1969) by Hugh Monahan, Log Hut on the St. Maurice (1862) and Paysage d'hiver, Laval (1849) by Cornelius Krieghoff, After The Bath (1890) by Paul Peel, Site du : "Combat de la Grange" September 25, 1775 (1839) by Louise-A

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_film_shining_kubrick_0015 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
Four etchings by John Webber appear in the film, A Man of Nootka Sound (1778), A Woman of Oonalashka (1784), A Woman of Prince William Sound (1784), and A Man of Van Diemen's Land (1777).[41] Webber accompanied James Cook on his third voyage to Hawaii, New Zealand, and Vancouver Island.[42][43]
Roger Ebert notes that the film does not really have a "reliable observer", with the possible exception 

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_film_shining_kubrick_0017 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
Ghosts are the implied explanation for Jack's seemingly physically impossible escape from the locked storeroom. In an interview of Kubrick by scholar Michel Ciment, the director made comments about the scene in the book that may imply he similarly thought of the scene in the film as a key reveal in this dichotomy:
It seemed to strike an extraordinary balance between the psychological and the super

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_film_shining_kubrick_0019 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
Dahlquist's argument is that Delbert Grady, the 1920s butler, and Charles Grady, the 1970s caretaker, rather than being either two people or the same are two 'manifestations' of a similar entity; a part permanently at the hotel (Delbert) and the part which is given the choice of whether to join the legacy of the hotel's murderous past (Charles), just as the man in the photo is not exactly Jack Tor

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_film_shining_kubrick_0020 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
Among Kubrick's other doubling/mirroring effects in the film:[49]
The ending photograph has been described as "iconic".[50] The provenance of the original photo used in the ending shot was discovered in April 2025. Conspiracy theories about its source have been discussed since the release of The Shining. Identified on screen as a July 4 ball at the Overlook Hotel in 1921, the real event depicted w

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_film_shining_kubrick_0025 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
In 1977, a Warner Bros. executive, John Calley, sent Kubrick the proofs of what would become the novel.[65] Its author, Stephen King, was already at that time a best-selling author who, after the blockbuster of Carrie, could boast of successes in adaptations for the big screen. For his part, Kubrick had been considering directing a horror film for some time; a few years before, while Barry Lyndon 

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_film_shining_kubrick_0028 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
Although Nicholson initially suggested that Jessica Lange would be a better fit for the role of Wendy Torrance,[83] Shelley Duvall knew early that she was the one cast for the role (Nicholson would work with Lange on his next movie, The Postman Always Rings Twice). Wendy's character in the film differs from the novel, appearing less capable and more vulnerable. Throughout filming, Kubrick pushed D

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_film_shining_kubrick_0032 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
Outtakes of the opening panorama shots were later used by Ridley Scott for the closing moments of the original cut of the film Blade Runner (1982).[95]
The Shining had a very prolonged and arduous production period, often with very long workdays. Principal photography took over a year to complete, due to Kubrick's highly methodical nature. Actress Shelley Duvall frequently argued with Kubrick on s

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_film_shining_kubrick_0034 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
On July 24, 1978, Kubrick screened David Lynch's Eraserhead (1977) to the cast and crew. He did this to convey the mood he wanted to achieve as well as to study Lynch and Alan Splet's highly regarded sound design on the independent film.[103] George and Marcia Lucas, at Elstree for pre-production on The Empire Strikes Back, also attended this screening. According to first assistant editor Gill Smi

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_film_shining_kubrick_0037 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
This required the Steadicam to be on a special mount resembling a wheelchair, in which the operator sat while pulling a platform with the sound man. The weight of the rig and its occupants proved to be too much for the original tires, resulting in a blowout one day that almost caused a serious crash. Solid tires were then mounted on the rig. Kubrick also had a highly accurate speedometer mounted o

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_film_shining_kubrick_0040 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
If Jack did indeed freeze to death in the labyrinth, of course his body was found û and sooner rather than later, since Dick Hallorann alerted the forest rangers to serious trouble at the hotel. If Jack's body was not found, what happened to it? Was it never there? Was it absorbed into the past and does that explain Jack's presence in that final photograph of a group of hotel party-goers in 1921? 

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_film_shining_kubrick_0047 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
Various theatrical posters were used during the original 1980û1981 international release cycle,[141][142][143][144][145] but in the U.S., where the film first opened, the primary poster and newspaper advert was designed by noted Hollywood graphic designer Saul Bass.[142][146][147][148][149][150] Bass and Kubrick reportedly went through over 300 potential designs before settling on the final design

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_film_shining_kubrick_0050 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
Neither Gene Siskel nor Roger Ebert reviewed the film on their television show Sneak Previews when it was first released,[160] but in his review for the Chicago Sun-Times, Ebert complained that it was hard to connect with any of the characters.[161] In his Chicago Tribune review, Siskel gave the film two stars out of four and called it "a crashing disappointment. The biggest surprise is that it co

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_film_shining_kubrick_0057 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
Horror film critic Peter Bracke, reviewing the Blu-ray release in High-Def Digest, wrote:
Just as the ghostly apparitions of the film's fictional Overlook Hotel would play tricks on the mind of poor Jack Torrance, so too has the passage of time changed the perception of The Shining itself. Many of the same reviewers who lambasted the film for "not being scary" enough back in 1980 now rank it among

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_film_shining_kubrick_0059 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
Stephen King has been quoted as saying that although Kubrick made a film with memorable imagery, it was poor as an adaptation[202] and that it is the only adaptation of his novels that he could "remember hating".[203] In his 1981 nonfiction book Danse Macabre, he noted that Kubrick was among those "filmmakers whose particular visions are so clear and fierce that ... fear of failure never becomes a

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_film_shining_kubrick_0060 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
The novel, written while King was suffering from alcoholism, contains an autobiographical element. King expressed disappointment that some themes, such as the disintegration of family and the dangers of alcoholism, are less present in the film. King also viewed the casting of Nicholson as a mistake, arguing it would result in a rapid realization among audiences that Jack would go insane, due to Ni

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_film_shining_kubrick_0061 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
In an interview with the BBC, King criticized Kubrick's Wendy, stating that she is "basically just there to scream and be stupid, and that's not the woman that I wrote about."[206] King's Wendy is a strong and independent woman on a professional and emotional level; to Kubrick, on the other hand, it did not seem consistent that such a woman had long endured the personality of Jack Torrance.[72]
Ki

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_film_shining_kubrick_0065 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
Mike Flanagan, director of the film adaptation of Doctor Sleep, would reconcile the differences between novel and film versions of The Shining there. Doctor Sleep is a direct adaptation of its novel counterpart, which itself is a sequel to the novel version of The Shining, but is also a continuation of Kubrick's film; in explaining the latter, Flanagan expressed, "The Shining is so ubiquitous and 

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_film_shining_kubrick_0066 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
In the film, the motive of the ghosts is apparently to "reclaim" Jack (although Grady expresses an interest in Danny's "shining" ability), who seems to be a reincarnation of a previous caretaker of the hotel, as suggested by the 1920s photograph of Jack at the end of the film and Jack's repeated claims to have "not just a dΘjα vu".[220] The film is more focused on Jack (as opposed to Danny) than t

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_film_shining_kubrick_0067 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
The novel initially presents Jack as likable and well-intentioned, yet haunted by the demons of alcohol and authority issues. Nonetheless, he becomes gradually overwhelmed by what he sees as the evil forces in the hotel. At the novel's conclusion, it is suggested that the evil hotel forces have possessed Jack's body and proceeded to destroy all that is left of his mind during a final showdown with

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_film_shining_kubrick_0068 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
The film prolongs Jack's struggle with writer's block. Kubrick's co-screenwriter Diane Johnson believes that in King's novel, Jack's discovery of the scrapbook of clippings in the boiler room of the hotel, which gives him new ideas for a novel, catalyzes his possession by the ghosts of the hotel, while at the same time unblocking his writing. Jack is no longer a blocked writer, but now filled with

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_film_shining_kubrick_0069 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
From Thomas Allen Nelson's Kubrick: Inside a Film Artist's Maze: "When Jack moves through the reception area on his way to a 'shining' over the model maze, he throws a yellow tennis ball past a stuffed bear and Danny's Big Wheel, which rests on the very spot (a Navajo circle design) where Hallorann will be murdered." Jack's tennis ball mysteriously rolls into Danny's circle of toy cars just before

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_film_shining_kubrick_0070 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
Although Danny has supernatural powers in both versions, the novel makes it clear that his apparent imaginary friend "Tony" really is a projection of hidden parts of his own psyche, though heavily amplified by Danny's psychic "shining" abilities. At the end it is revealed that Danny Torrance's middle name is "Anthony".[236][original research?]
Wendy Torrance in the film is relatively meek, submiss

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_film_shining_kubrick_0071 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
Co-screenwriter Diane Johnson stated that in her contributions to the script, Wendy had more dialogue, and believes that Kubrick cut many of her lines due to his dissatisfaction with Duvall's delivery. Johnson believes that the earlier draft of the script portrayed Wendy as a more rounded character.[239] The "Wendy Theory" claims that Kubrick made Wendy, not Jack, the psychotic character. Shifts i

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_film_shining_kubrick_0072 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
From Kubrick: Inside a Film Artist's Maze: Ullman tells Jack that the hotel's season runs from May 15 to October 30, meaning that the Torrances moved in on Halloween (October 31). On Ullmann's desk next to a small American flag sits a metal cup containing pencils and a pen û and a miniature replica of an ax.
"When Ullman, himself all smiles, relates as a footnote the story about the former caretak

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_film_shining_kubrick_0073 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
In the novel Jack recovers his sanity and goodwill through the intervention of Danny; this does not occur in the film. Writing in Cinefantastique magazine, Frederick Clarke suggests, "Instead of playing a normal man who becomes insane, Nicholson portrays a crazy man attempting to remain sane."[248] In the novel, Jack's final act is to enable Wendy and Danny to escape the hotel before it explodes d

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_film_shining_kubrick_0074 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
In the film, the hotel possibly derives its malevolent energy from being built on a Native American burial ground. In the novel, the reason for the hotel's manifestation of evil is possibly explained by a theme present in King's 1975 novel 'Salem's Lot as well as Shirley Jackson's 1959 novel The Haunting of Hill House: a physical place may absorb the evils that transpire there and manifest them as

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_film_shining_kubrick_0079 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
Vince Gilligan, being a fan of Kubrick and his "non-submersible moments", has included references to Kubrick movies in many of his works.[273][274] "I'm happy to see that his inspiration has shown in noticeable ways in our work in Breaking Bad and Better Call Saul", says Gilligan.[275] Breaking Bad's 2010 episode "Sunset" has a cop radioing for assistance and begins, "KDK-12" û the radio address a

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_film_shining_kubrick_0081 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
In 2014, Warner Bros. Pictures began developing a film adaptation of Doctor Sleep (2013), Stephen King's sequel to his book, The Shining (1977).[287] In 2016, Akiva Goldsman announced that he would write and produce the film for Warner Bros.[288] For several years, Warner Bros could not secure a budget for the sequel nor for a prequel to The Shining to be called Overlook Hotel.[289] In June 2019, 

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_miniseries_shining_1997_0000 | SHINING_1997 ---
The Shining (stylized as Stephen King's The Shining) is a 1997 three-episode horror television miniseries based on the 1977 Stephen King novel of the same name. Directed by Mick Garris from King's teleplay, it is the second adaptation of King's book after the 1980 film by Stanley Kubrick and was written and produced by King due to his dissatisfaction with Kubrick's version. The miniseries was shot

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_miniseries_shining_1997_0001 | SHINING_1997 ---
Originally airing from April 27 to May 1, 1997 on the American television network ABC, The Shining enjoyed a favorable reception when it first aired. It was a ratings hit, being in the top 20 of daily viewership numbers for all three episodes; acclaimed by critics for its careful pacing, makeup, depth, sound editing and creepy atmosphere; and won two Primetime Emmy and two Saturn Awards. However, 

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_miniseries_shining_1997_0004 | SHINING_1997 ---
Danny brings Jackùa bloody nightmareùto himself, briefly, and tells him about the boiler. ôJackö races to fix it, but Danny shines to his father, who reverses the valve. Danny, Wendy, and Hallorann escape. Accepting his fate, Jack kills himself by triggering a massive steam explosion that levels the Overlook.
Ten years later at around the age of 17, Danny graduates from high school; he now physica

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_miniseries_shining_1997_0007 | SHINING_1997 ---
Aside from the motive behind the creation of the miniseries, the 1997 rendition featured an important set piece that helped to inspire the original story: The Stanley Hotel in Estes Park, Colorado. King used the hotel that inspired him to write the book as the miniseries' location, with some interior shots in stages also in Denver.[8] Garris tried to make the hotel feel as "enclosed" as possible t

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_miniseries_shining_1997_0010 | SHINING_1997 ---
The first part of The Shining garnered 19.8 million viewers, ranking #12 for the week with a household rating of 12.5 and a market share of 19.[citation needed] The second part also ranked #12 for the week, with 18.3 million viewers, a 12.1 rating and a 20 share.[citation needed] The third part ranked #14 for the week, with 18.2 million viewers, an 11.9 rating and a 16 share.[citation needed]
The 

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_shining_novel_shining_novel_0010 | SHINING_NOVEL ---
The novel was adapted into a 1980 feature film of the same name directed by Stanley Kubrick and co-written with Diane Johnson. King himself wrote a screenplay, which was initially very faithful to the novel but rejected by Kubrick.[23] Although King himself remains disappointed with the adaptation, having criticized its handling of the book's major themes and of Wendy's character, it is regarded a

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_stand_1994_miniseries_stand_1994_0006 | STAND_1994 ---
Warner Bros. initially wanted King to do a single, two-hour script, but he ended up turning in a screenplay that was over 400 pages (equivalent to six hours in length).[6] Creepshow was released in 1982 to commercial success,[3] and The Stand project garnered the interest of Warner Bros., a company that placed it into development.[6] The budget for The Stand was set around $15û25 million just afte

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_stand_1994_miniseries_stand_1994_0007 | STAND_1994 ---
Hollywood significantly increased their interest in screen adaptations of King's work after the box office success of Pet Sematary (1989), and many were being pitched in studios following the film's release; one of these was an adaptation of The Stand, which was reported in a January 1990 Cinefantastique article to be "the most anticipated" developing King project.[11] Stephen King's most popular 

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_stand_1994_miniseries_stand_1994_0012 | STAND_1994 ---
Bates's character, Rae Flowers, was originally a man (Ray Flowers), but when Bates became available, King û who wanted her to play the part û rewrote the role as a woman. King played Teddy Weizak, the first character he played that was intelligent and not a typecast "country asshole". He has less of a presence in the miniseries, as King "had a lot of other fish on a lot of other griddles that I wa

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_stand_1994_miniseries_stand_1994_0016 | STAND_1994 ---
The jail sequences were shot for three days at the sex offender wing of the Utah State Prison.[41] However, the effects crew who were working on dead body dummies in the cells were unaware of this on the first day of shooting at the location and assumed it was an unused wing.[41] The prison actually moved the sex offenders out of their cells for the miniseries, but the prisoners' belongings were l

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_stand_1994_miniseries_stand_1994_0017 | STAND_1994 ---
While many effects companies were interested in working on The Stand, Garris chose a colleague he knew for a very long time but never worked on a project with: Steve Johnson.[35] Johnson had a been fan of King's books since twelve years before he started working on the miniseries, and the original novel was his favorite book by the author; he described it as "a dream come true" to work with King o

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_stand_1994_miniseries_stand_1994_0020 | STAND_1994 ---
While Tom Barham of New York's Image Group company handled the morphing FX, Garris came up with the idea of having Flagg's head morph executed in a way different from the traditional media morph of one head design just melting into another: inside out.[35] Not only was it different, but also a way to work around the limited budget as the morphing could look "active" without the camera having to mo

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_stand_2020_miniseries_stand_2020_0002 | STAND_2020 ---
On February 25, 2014, Josh Boone was hired to write and direct the adaptation.[18] He later revealed that he wanted Christian Bale to play Randall Flagg and Matthew McConaughey for the role of Stu Redman.[19] By September 10, 2014, the script had been completed and pre-production was underway.[20] In November, Boone planned to split his adaptation into four full-length feature films in an effort t

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_stand_2020_miniseries_stand_2020_0003 | STAND_2020 ---
By August 1, Marsden, Heard, Young, and Zaga were all cast in the series.[34] According to news reports, Stephen King wrote an entirely different ending to the final chapter of the series that is different from either the book or coda. The last episodes were written by King and his son Owen.[28] On September 11, 2019, Alexander Skarsgσrd was cast as Randall Flagg.[35] Confirmed cast members includ

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_stand_stand_novel_1978_0009 | STAND_NOVEL_1978 ---
The Stand was also planned by King as an epic story akin to The Lord of the Rings in a contemporary American setting:
For a long timeùten years, at leastùI had wanted to write a fantasy epic like The Lord of the Rings, only with an American setting. I just couldn't figure out how to do it. Then . . . after my wife and kids and I moved to Boulder, Colorado, I saw a 60 Minutes segment on CBW (chemic

--- en_wikipedia_org_the_stand_stand_novel_1978_0010 | STAND_NOVEL_1978 ---
While writing The Stand, King nearly stopped because of writer's block.[5] Eventually, he reached the conclusion that the heroes were becoming too complacent, and were beginning to repeat all the same mistakes of their old society. In an attempt to resolve this, he added the part of the storyline where Harold and Nadine construct a bomb, which explodes in a Free Zone committee meeting, killing Nic

--- https_allthingsfadra_com_the_stand_1994_vs_the_stand_2020_st_0001 | STAND_COMPARISON ---
It was cheesy. It was fun. It was dated. And it was the perfect precursor to the Paramount+ reboot of The Stand which started airing in December 2020.
And now starts the inevitable comparisons. I found myself watching both versions and turning to my family saying, ôWell, in the book, this part was differentàö Yes, I am that annoying person.
After hours and hours and hours of The Stand, I thought i

--- https_allthingsfadra_com_the_stand_1994_vs_the_stand_2020_st_0003 | STAND_COMPARISON ---
I think both actors brought their own flair to the role, eliciting both fear and adoration. While I think the story worked against the 2020 version of Randall Flagg, Skarsgaard brings a slight edge to the role.
WHO WORE IT BEST? Alexander Skaarsgard, 2020
Larry Underwood is such a complex character that perhaps has the biggest character growth in the book. I always felt like Adam Storke (1994) was

--- https_allthingsfadra_com_the_stand_1994_vs_the_stand_2020_st_0009 | STAND_COMPARISON ---
The story ends with them making it to the coast of Maine and we get a sense that new life will begin again. And we see Flagg will begin again as well, much like in the novel.
The Production
Changes to the story and changes to the cast are to be expected. Some worked and some didnÆt but thereÆs one primary complaint I have about the 2020 version of The Stand.
The Timeline
The original miniseries ac

--- https_screenrant_com_salems_lot_biggest_differences_miniseri_0002 | SALEMS_LOT_COMPARISON ---
Biggest Differences Between Salem's Lot Book & Series
King's novel approaches the vampire genre by paying homage to Bram Stoker's Dracula through his character of Kurt Barlow. Barlow, inspired by Dracula's suave, sophisticated manner, presents as human and proposes the notion of an ancient vampire existing in modern day. The small, sleepy town of Jerusalem's Lot serves as an eerie backdrop for a c

--- https_screenrant_com_salems_lot_biggest_differences_miniseri_0003 | SALEMS_LOT_COMPARISON ---
The original miniseries also made changes when it came to the character of Father Callahan. While he served an important role in the novel, his presence bringing up discussions of religion and good versus evil, the series severely reduced the character of Father Callahan. King has pointed out that this causes the series to lack certain themes important to the novel, particularly omitting the stron

--- https_screenrant_com_salems_lot_movies_miniseries_ranked_wor_0001 | SALEMS_LOT_COMPARISON ---
A Return to Salem's Lot (1987)
No Available Rotten Tomatoes Tomatometer Score
A Return to Salem's Lot is the worst adaptation of Salem's Lot, with bizarre touches that can't replicate the underlying horror of the original. Directed by famously quirky filmmaker Larry Cohen, A Return to Salem's Lot is largely disconnected from the original story outside of a shared setting in the town of Jerusalem's

--- https_screenrant_com_salems_lot_movies_miniseries_ranked_wor_0003 | SALEMS_LOT_COMPARISON ---
However, there's a rushed quality to the new version of Salem's Lot that undercuts some of the strength of the original, with an over-reliance on jump-scares that undercuts the film's better moments of subtle scares. The first half in particular speeds through the story, with the plot advancing at a fast clip for the sake of itself rather than unfolding at a natrual clip. This costs some of the ri

--- https_screenrant_com_salems_lot_movies_miniseries_ranked_wor_0005 | SALEMS_LOT_COMPARISON ---
Salem's Lot (2004)
68% on Rotten Tomatoes Tomatometer Score
Although it didn't attract as much attention as its more famous predecessor, there's honestly a lot to like about the 2004 version of Salem's Lot. A TV miniseries starring Rob Lowe as Ben, the 2004 version benefits from the longer run-time. This gives the cast more time to explore their versions of the characters, imbuing the story with a

--- https_www_cbr_com_salems_lot_barlow_nosferatu_similarties_mi_0002 | SALEMS_LOT_COMPARISON ---
Their Grand Guignol excess came with another revelation for the author: E.C.'s vampires were American, not European. They drove modern cars, owned businesses, and looked like then-modern US citizens instead of desiccated 19th century aristocrats. Those concepts helped cement many of 'Salem's Lot's key themes, and as a monster poised to turn the town into his private fiefdom, Barlow is plenty scary

--- https_www_cbr_com_salems_lot_barlow_nosferatu_similarties_mi_0003 | SALEMS_LOT_COMPARISON ---
In other words, he's a lot like a thousand other vampires in a thousand other far more forgettable horror stories, with very little to distinguish him from the bloodsucking pack. That was easier to slide past in 1975. Anne Rice's Interview with the Vampire was still a year away, and Bela Lugosi and Christopher Lee were more or less the only games in town as far as pop culture vampires went. Anythi

--- https_www_cbr_com_salems_lot_barlow_nosferatu_similarties_mi_0004 | SALEMS_LOT_COMPARISON ---
In Cinefantastique magazine Vol. 9 #2, producer Richard Kobritz cited the need to make Barlow frightening rather than sexy. "I just thought it would be suicidal on our part to have a vampire that talks. What kind of voice do you put behind a vampire? You can't do Bela Lugosi, or you're going to get a laugh." The comment highlights how King could get away with sparse descriptors and still achieve t

--- https_www_cbr_com_salems_lot_barlow_nosferatu_similarties_mi_0006 | SALEMS_LOT_COMPARISON ---
The 2024 movie solves one of the other big challenges in adapting the book: balancing Barlow against Straker, who either feels underused (in the case of the 2004 version) or essentially substituting for the vampire, like in the 1979 miniseries. The human half of the duo acts as build-up in the book, giving way to Barlow gradually in order to save the vampire's true menace to the end. That can conf

--- https_www_cbr_com_the_stand_biggest_differences_stephen_king_0001 | STAND_COMPARISON ---
To differentiate itself from the previous 1994 ABC miniseries adaptation of The Stand, which similarly progressed linearly, the CBS All Access interpretation of the story has the glimpses of the contagion's outbreak shown largely in flashbacks after the first episode. While the change in narrative approach allows this particular adaptation to hone in on the battle between Boulder and Vegas, it als

--- https_www_cbr_com_the_stand_biggest_differences_stephen_king_0003 | STAND_COMPARISON ---
Trashcan Man
One of the more bizarre characters in any version of The Stand is Trashcan Man, a pyromaniac who pathologically sets anything he can on fire and who is summoned by Flagg to join him in Vegas. In the novel, Trash is transported to Vegas by a psychopath known as The Kid before Flagg kills the escort and tasks Trash with obtaining weaponry for his forces. Trash uncontrollably causes a fi

--- https_www_cbr_com_the_stand_biggest_differences_stephen_king_0004 | STAND_COMPARISON ---
In the novel, Nick appears to Tom as a ghost and helps guide him to the injured Stu, who accidentally broke his leg en route to confront Flagg in Vegas. The two shelter in a cabin for the winter before returning to Boulder while the adaptation omits the spectral Nick entirely, with Tom finding Stu on his own and the two returning to Boulder by Christmas.
Frannie in the Well
The biggest addition to

--- https_www_slashfilm_com_699756_why_stanley_kubrick_decided_t_0000 | SHINING_COMPARISON ---
Will Avengers: Endgame's re-release, titled Avengers Endgame: Encore, give the Marvel film the biggest box office record of all? Here's how things look.
Read More
- 
    
  - 
            Sitcoms have had to to adapt to streaming era, but the 2020s have still delivered these five shows that are sure to be future classics. Read More
  - 
            Many of the best TV comedy series of 2026 are as 

--- https_www_slashfilm_com_973468_the_stand_miniseries_let_step_0001 | STAND_COMPARISON ---
The 2020 miniseries differs from all the previous iterations in one vital element: The ending has been changed. The ninth episode of the series, called "The Circle Closes" includes a coda to the story that King didn't include in either version of his novel. In a 2020 interview with EW, King revealed he took the opportunity to get on a record an ending very reminiscent of "The Last Temptation of Ch

--- https_www_slashfilm_com_973468_the_stand_miniseries_let_step_0002 | STAND_COMPARISON ---
In his celebrated 2000 essay "On Writing: A Memoir of the Craft," King admits that the "I don't know" was born of an inability to write anything that didn't sound corny or preachy. He felt "The Stand" should end without a moral, leaving humanity somewhat adrift. It may be here that King's own notorious inability to end his stories strongly began. Some 40 years on, King, who wrote "the Circle Close

--- https_www_slashfilm_com_973468_the_stand_miniseries_let_step_0003 | STAND_COMPARISON ---
With "The Circle Closes," however, Stephen King seems to have added an epilogue that, while still not providing a clear moral, seems to have shut the book on "The Stand" once and for all.
The new ending of "The Stand" resembles the flash-forward montage as seen in films like Martin Scorsese's "The Last Temptation of Christ," Spike Lee's "The 25th Hour," and David Lowery's "The Green Knight." In ea

--- stephenking_fandom_com_abagail_freemantle_stand_novel_1978_0005 | STAND_NOVEL_1978 ---
At sunrise, just as she predicted, Abagail dies.
Resigned, the four men decide they have little choice but to obey Abagail's final instructions. Hundreds of miles into their journey, in the Utah badlands Stu breaks his leg and must be left behind. In the miniseries, Mother Abagail appears to Stu in a dream shortly before he is rescued by Tom Cullen to let Stu know that he must witness what is abou

--- stephenking_fandom_com_danny_torrance_shining_novel_0000 | SHINING_NOVEL ---
Daniel Anthony "Dannyö Torrance is the central protagonist of the Stephen King multiverse.
Serving as the main protagonist of Stephen King's novel, The Shining, its 1980 film, the 1997 miniseries, Doctor Sleep and it's 2019 film. He is also a mentioned character in Castle Rock TV Series.
He is the son of Jack and Wendy Torrance, the older half-brother of Lucy Stone and the uncle of Abra Stone (in 

--- stephenking_fandom_com_danny_torrance_shining_novel_0001 | SHINING_NOVEL ---
In the book, Danny appears to be a lonely, curious yet nervous boy who loves both his parents but has a particular love towards his father. Danny has terrifying visions of The Overlook Hotel which worry and disturb him. He arrives with Wendy and Jack at The Overlook Hotel on Closing Day, where he finds the hotel is extremely busy with guests checking out and staff assisting guests leave as well as

--- stephenking_fandom_com_dick_hallorann_films_shining_kubrick_0002 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
While in his Florida home watching a news broadcast, Dick communicated with Danny or had a premonition on Jack entering Room 237. Arriving to the hotel in a snowcat and getting inside, Hallorann calls for the Torrance family. Before he got past the last two pillars, Jack Torrance comes out and strikes him in his chest with an axe, killing him. However in the novel, Dick survived Jack's chaos and m

--- stephenking_fandom_com_donald_callahan_salems_lot_novel_0002 | SALEMS_LOT_NOVEL ---
Callahan learns that there are three types of vampires. The Type Ones are the most powerful ones and are almost immortal. They can spread vampirism to others and create Type Two vampires. Kurt Barlow was a Type One. Type Twos are more common and can create other Type Twos or Type Threes. Lastly, the Type Threes cannot spread vampirism but can spread diseases that travel by blood, such as HIV. Call

--- stephenking_fandom_com_donald_callahan_salems_lot_novel_0006 | SALEMS_LOT_NOVEL ---
Eventually, once Jake reaches relative safety, he's overwhelmed and swarmed by the vampires. Before the beasts can assault him, he once again escapes their clutches by shooting himself under the chin. Before taking his own life, he converses briefly with Roland, who bears witness to the scene across time and space. His final words to Roland and in life were a benediction to the Gunslinger: "May yo

--- stephenking_fandom_com_donald_callahan_salems_lot_novel_0007 | SALEMS_LOT_NOVEL ---
The original draft of Salem's Lot originally depicted a different fate for Callahan. Rather than forced to drink Barlow's blood and leaving town damned, he marks the vampire with a knife before committing suicide. Furious, the vampire desecrates the priest's body, decapitating it and hanging it upside down. This scene was changed by King before he originally published the story, though it was incl

--- stephenking_fandom_com_donald_callahan_salems_lot_novel_0008 | SALEMS_LOT_NOVEL ---
In the miniseries, Father Callahan is featured only as a minor character. He is played by James Gallery. Callahan is first briefly seen officiating at the funeral of Danny Glick. Later, Ben Mears and Susan Norton have a brief interview with him where they try to convince him to join them against the evil in the town. Callahan is skeptical and makes a brief comment on how the Church's view of evil 

--- stephenking_fandom_com_donald_callahan_salems_lot_novel_0009 | SALEMS_LOT_NOVEL ---
Mears confronts Callahan and chases him up some stairs where they struggle. Mears pushes Callahan out a window; the two of them land on a police car. The rest of the film is told in flashback as Ben explains to a hospital orderly why he attacked Callahan.
Callahan is generally portrayed as in the novel (although there is a scene with him browsing what could be a Satanic porn site), but after Barlo

--- stephenking_fandom_com_frances_goldsmith_stand_novel_1978_0000 | STAND_NOVEL_1978 ---
Frances Rebecca Goldsmith, aka "Frannie" or "Fran", is a main character in the novel The Stand, with a great deal of the story being narrated from her point of view.
Fran is also a protagonist in the 1994 and 2020 miniseries based on the novel of the same name. Her character is portrayed by Molly Ringwald and Odessa Young, respectively.
Warm, spirited, and often tomboyish, Fran is stated by Peter 

--- stephenking_fandom_com_harold_lauder_stand_novel_1978_0000 | STAND_NOVEL_1978 ---
Harold Emery Lauder is a supporting character and later antagonist in the novel The Stand. In the 1994 TV miniseries, he is portrayed by Corin Nemec. In the 2020 miniseries, he is portrayed by Owen Teague.
At the time of the superflu epidemic, Harold is a sixteen-year-old resident of Ogunquit, Maine. He has an indifferent mother and a brutish and overbearing father. His popular sister Amy is shall

--- stephenking_fandom_com_harold_lauder_stand_novel_1978_0005 | STAND_NOVEL_1978 ---
He writes a suicide note initially stating that "I was misled", but quickly rejects that statement as cowardly and dishonest. He continues writing, taking responsibility for his actions, and expresses remorse and apologizes for them, though he knows he cannot be forgiven. He signs this note, "Hawk," as a way of trying one final time to accept the best version of himself that had existed briefly in

--- stephenking_fandom_com_jack_torrance_films_shining_kubrick_0000 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
Jack Torrance is the main antagonist of The Shining (1980) and a posthumous antagonist of the Doctor Sleep (2019).
In contrast to its book counterpart, who was an initially good but deeply flawed man whose flaws were ruthlessly exploited by the evil hotel, and who eventually redeemed himself after his fall to darkness, Kubrick's Torrance is from the start an abusive, menacing, hostile, and borderl

--- stephenking_fandom_com_jack_torrance_films_shining_kubrick_0001 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
Jack was a writer who accepted the job of winter caretaker for the Overlook Hotel, despite being informed of the building's grisly past and reputation as a cursed place (which he shrugged off as a superstition), and he took his wife Wendy and son Danny with him to the hotel, thinking that the solitude of the place would help inspire him in his writing as well. He shows his first sign of going insa

--- stephenking_fandom_com_jack_torrance_films_shining_kubrick_0002 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
. Not long after this, Lloyd the Bartender mysteriously appears (implying the Overlook Hotel may have taken up Jack's deal) and offers Jack fine alcohol on the house. Jack accepts the bourbon, breaking the alcohol abstinence he had been taking for the past few months. Lloyd and Jack act as if they've known each other for years, as the latter tells Lloyd that he's not happy with both his family and

--- stephenking_fandom_com_jack_torrance_films_shining_kubrick_0003 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
. When he gets back, he lies to his wife about not seeing anyone in the room, in order to cover up his tracks, claiming that Danny injured himself. When she asks for them to leave the hotel, he furiously berates and insults her, claiming that he absolutely refuses to leave the hotel before storming off in a fit of rage. When he gets to the barroom, it's now filled with ghosts before reuniting with

--- stephenking_fandom_com_jack_torrance_films_shining_kubrick_0004 | SHINING_KUBRICK ---
. Jack then heads back to the radio room and removes capacitors from the radio, rendering it inoperable. He then proceeds to remove the fuel injection manifold from the snowcat, also rendering it unable to start, preventing Danny and Wendy from leaving. After Wendy discovers just how far gone Jack is and tries to convince him they need to leave, Jack becomes angry and threatens her life. Wendy the

--- stephenking_fandom_com_jack_torrance_shining_novel_0002 | SHINING_NOVEL ---
The evil spirits that inhabited the Overlook Hotel would eventually drive Jack insane by way of drowning him in his alcoholism, past trauma, and fears of becoming as abusive as his father. The spirits possess him into attempting to murder his family with a roque mallet, which is revealed when his wife realized that 'redrum', the word that Jack had been writing on the walls, means murder backwards.

--- stephenking_fandom_com_jack_torrance_shining_novel_0003 | SHINING_NOVEL ---
Jack appeared in the novel Doctor Sleep, in which Danny (as an adult, went by "Dan") discovered that he had a half-sister named Lucy, and a niece named Abra who had similar abilities to him ù only more powerful. Dan saw a vision of his father at what used to be the Overlook Hotel near the end of the novel.

--- stephenking_fandom_com_jack_torrance_shining_novel_0004 | SHINING_NOVEL ---
In the novel, Jack Torrance is a loving but troubled father who cares deeply for Wendy and Danny but does not know how to show it properly, as he is a diagnosed sociopath whom lacks guilt and remorse but yet still had some empathy left in him. Jack's alcoholism and violent temper had lost him a job as a teacher of literature at a prestigious New England prep school. One day he catches a student he

--- stephenking_fandom_com_jack_torrance_shining_novel_0006 | SHINING_NOVEL ---
Eventually, he goes mad thanks to the influence of the hotelÆs ghosts and attempts to kill Wendy and Danny. His plan does not work though and Wendy and Danny escape with Dick Hallorann who came to save Wendy and Danny as the hotel boiler explodes, killing Jack and destroying the Overlook completely.
Jack Torrance does not appear in Doctor Sleep until the very end in which he appears as a ghost at 

--- stephenking_fandom_com_kurt_barlow_salems_lot_1979_0000 | SALEMS_LOT_1979 ---
In Salem's Lot (1979), Barlow was significantly different from his novel counterpart; while Kurt Barlow in the novel resembled an ordinary human being, in the 1979 mini-series, he was depicted with a Nosferatu-like appearance. Interestingly enough, in The Dark Tower, it was mentioned in the beginning that "Type One" Vampires (such as Barlow) were horribly disfigured, mutant-like creatures whose te

--- stephenking_fandom_com_kurt_barlow_salems_lot_novel_0002 | SALEMS_LOT_NOVEL ---
When Father Callahan and Mark headed over to Mark's parents to explain the danger that the family was in, the power was suddenly cut and Barlow appeared. He killed Mark's parents by smashing their heads together, but did not infect them. Barlow then took Mark hostage briefly. Callahan pulled out his cross in an attempt to drive Barlow off, and for a time it worked, until Barlow challenged him to t

--- stephenking_fandom_com_mark_petrie_salems_lot_novel_0000 | SALEMS_LOT_NOVEL ---
Mark Petrie is a character from Salem's Lot.
Mark is a young boy and resident of Jerusalem's Lot, Maine. He is one of the first to realize that vampires are beginning to overtake the town.
Early in the novel, the school bully, Richie Boddin, in an attempt to assert his rule over the playground, tries to beat up Mark but finds that Mark is a formidable opponent. Boddin fails miserably against the s

--- stephenking_fandom_com_nadine_cross_stand_novel_1978_0000 | STAND_NOVEL_1978 ---
Nadine Cross is one of the main characters in the novel The Stand. In the 1994 TV miniseries, she is portrayed by Laura San Giacomo. Amber Heard portrays Nadine in the The Stand (2020 Miniseries).
Nadine Cross was an orphan adopted at the age of four and a half months. Her adoptive parents and their biological son were killed in a car accident when she was six, whereupon she went to live with thei

--- stephenking_fandom_com_nick_andros_stand_novel_1978_0000 | STAND_NOVEL_1978 ---
Nicholas "Nick" Andros (1968-1990) is one of the main protagonists in the novel The Stand (alongside Stuart Redman, Fran Goldsmith, and Larry Underwood). In the 1994 television miniseries, he is portrayed by Rob Lowe. Henry Zaga portrays Nick in the 2020 Miniseries.
Nick was a young deaf-mute man and one of the few survivors of "Captain Trips", a deadly strain of flu that was created by the govern

--- stephenking_fandom_com_overlook_hotel_shining_novel_0000 | SHINING_NOVEL ---
The Overlook Hotel is a major antagonist of the Stephen King multiverse.
It serves as the main antagonist of the novel The Shining, its 1980 film adaptation, its 1997 miniseries, the overarching antagonist of its 2013 sequel Doctor Sleep, and its 2019 film adaptation of the same name. It is also a minor antagonist in the 2021 novel Billy Summers. It is also a mentioned in Misery, Castle Rock TV Se

--- stephenking_fandom_com_overlook_hotel_shining_novel_0001 | SHINING_NOVEL ---
In the film The Shining, the Overlook Hotel's exterior is represented by Timberline Lodge at Mt. Hood in Oregon. The interiors of the Overlook are based heavily on the Ahwahnee Hotel at Yosemite. The film's Colorado Lounge is a near copy of the Grand Lounge at Ahwahnee. The elevators and Lobby of both are also nearly identical. It has been noticed that from scene to scene the layout of the Overloo

--- stephenking_fandom_com_randall_flagg_stand_novel_1978_0001 | STAND_NOVEL_1978 ---
He often appears under different names; most are abbreviated by the initials R.F., but there are exceptions to this rule; in The Dark Tower series, the name most often associated with Flagg is Walter o'Dim, yet he is also known as The Man in Black, Marten Broadcloak, but his real name is Walter Padick. Flagg is described as "an accomplished sorcerer and a devoted servant of the Outer Dark" with ge

--- stephenking_fandom_com_randall_flagg_stand_novel_1978_0003 | STAND_NOVEL_1978 ---
He was given to a mill owner and his wife to be brought up to learn the ways of men. At thirteen he grew bored and burned down his home, then sought out his father Maerlyn. The next year, he was raped by a fellow wanderer, but instead of returning home he went on to fulfill his destiny.
Over the years, it is implied that Walter learned the ways of Dark magic and became a very powerful sorcerer and

--- stephenking_fandom_com_richard_straker_salems_lot_novel_0000 | SALEMS_LOT_NOVEL ---
Richard Throckett Straker was the secondary antagonist in Stephen King's novel Salem's Lot.
In the original novel, Straker was Kurt Barlow's "familiar" or human thrall. All of Barlow's business concerns were enacted by him. Straker bought the Marsten House and prepared the way for his master. He was presented as a Satanist and showed his devotion by sacrificing Ralphie Glick to unhallow the town f

--- stephenking_fandom_com_richard_straker_salems_lot_novel_0001 | SALEMS_LOT_NOVEL ---
In Salem's Lot (1979), Straker was the main antagonist and a more prominent villain than Barlow, unlike the novel, and was alive until the climax of the mini-series. Though seemingly human, that version of Straker turned out to be someone more with incredible strength, and it was implied that he possessed some kind of supernatural power: Straker summoned a fast wind as he abducted Ralphie Glick in

--- stephenking_fandom_com_richard_straker_salems_lot_novel_0002 | SALEMS_LOT_NOVEL ---
In 'Salem's Lot (2004), Straker's name was once again changed, that time into Richard Thomas Straker. Although Straker had more screen time than Barlow in that version also, his role was somewhat reduced from that of the original mini-series. He was also never actually seen in any of the same scenes with Barlow. In that version, Straker was killed as in the novel: he was left hanging upside down f

--- stephenking_fandom_com_salem_s_lot_1979_miniseries_salems_lo_0003 | SALEMS_LOT_1979 ---
Although generally the same story, the television adaptation takes several liberties with King's source novel. Many characters have been combined or merely deleted, as have certain subplots, and the character of Barlow is totally different in the miniseries from how he is in the novel. However, Stephen King praised Paul Monash's screenplay and commented "Monash has succeeded in combining the chara

--- stephenking_fandom_com_salem_s_lot_1979_miniseries_salems_lo_0004 | SALEMS_LOT_1979 ---
"We went back to the old German Nosferatu concept where he is the essence of evil, and not anything romantic or smarmy, or, you know, the rouge-cheeked, widow-peaked Dracula. I wanted nothing suave or sexual, because I just didn't think it'd work; we've seen too much of it. The other thing we did with the character which I think is an improvement is that Barlow does not speak. When he's killed at 

--- stephenking_fandom_com_salem_s_lot_1979_miniseries_salems_lo_0005 | SALEMS_LOT_1979 ---
Other changes by Kobritz included having the final confrontation with Barlow in the cellar of the Marsten House whereas in the book it is in the basement of Eva Miller's boarding house, a concept Kobritz felt "Just doesn't work. I mean, from a point of sheer construction in a well-written screenplay, he's got to reside in the inside of the Marsten House. He's a major star in the picture - the thir

--- stephenking_fandom_com_salem_s_lot_1979_miniseries_salems_lo_0007 | SALEMS_LOT_1979 ---
32. Conclusion (without overdub)
33. Conclusion (with timpani & horn overdu )
34. Main Title ( Feature Version ) / Vampires! (Feature Version)
35. End Credits (Feature Version)
After Warner Bros. acquired the rights to 'Salem's Lot, the studio sought to turn the 400-page novel by Stephen King into a feature film, while still remaining faithful to the source material. Producer Stirling Silliphant, 

--- stephenking_fandom_com_salem_s_lot_1979_miniseries_salems_lo_0008 | SALEMS_LOT_1979 ---
For the roles of Straker and Barlow, the villianous duo, James Mason and Reggie Nalder were chosen as they had been on the producer Richard Kobritz's personal "Wish List." Kobritz sent Mason a copy of the script, which he loved. MasonÆs wife, Clarissa Kaye-Mason, was also cast as Marjorie Glick. Nalder was less impressed. "The makeup and contact lenses were painful but I got used to them. I liked 

--- stephenking_fandom_com_stuart_redman_stand_novel_1978_0000 | STAND_NOVEL_1978 ---
Stuart Richard Redman is a major protagonist of the Stephen King multiverse.
Serving as one of the three main protagonists (alongside Larry Underwood and Nick Andros) of the novel The Stand, and its two miniseries of the same name.
He was an employee at the calculator plant of Arnette, Texas. He was one of the handful of survivors of the super flu known as "Captain Trips".
A quiet man from the fic

--- stephenking_fandom_com_stuart_redman_stand_novel_1978_0001 | STAND_NOVEL_1978 ---
Stu is shown to have had a slight wild streak as a young man, often sneaking across the border to Mexico with his friends to visit brothels. He did mature later on, though, and married a woman named, Norma. Sadly, Norma developed cancer (implied to be uterine cancer) and died after only about 18 months of marriage.
Four years after Norma's death, Stu is working at a calculator factory, and earning

--- stephenking_fandom_com_the_stand_stand_novel_1978_0000 | STAND_NOVEL_1978 ---
The Stand is the sixth book published by Stephen King; it is his fifth novel, and the fourth novel under his own name. The book was the last of King's novels published by Doubleday on October 3, 1978.
The novel is a post-apocalyptic horror/fantasy story that re-works the scenario of King's earlier short story, "Night Surf". A longer edition of the novel was later released in May 1990; King restore

--- stephenking_fandom_com_wendy_torrance_shining_novel_0000 | SHINING_NOVEL ---
Winifred "Wendy" Torrance is a major character of the Stephen King multiverse.
She serves as the main protagonist of Stephen King's novel The Shining, the 1980 film adaptation, the 1997 miniseries adaptation, and a posthumous character in its sequel Doctor Sleep, and its 2019 film adaptation.
She is the wife of Jack Torrance and the mother of Danny Torrance. In the 1980 film adaptation, she was po

--- stephenking_fandom_com_wendy_torrance_shining_novel_0002 | SHINING_NOVEL ---
In the novel, Wendy is depicted as a miserable, depressed, stay-at-home housewife whose marriage is extremely rocky. She is noted as being blonde and being very beautiful. An example of this is used when the Torrances arrive at the Overlook Hotel on Closing Day during the busy time with the guests leaving and several heads turn to stare at her legs. She is nervous at first and notices the quietnes

--- stephenking_fandom_com_wendy_torrance_shining_novel_0004 | SHINING_NOVEL ---
In the 2019 sequel Doctor Sleep, Wendy has passed away in 1999 from lung cancer, possibly caused from the explosion of the Overlook Hotel many years ago. However, she appears in the start of the book, living with Danny after the events of The Shining in a new apartment, traumatized and timid. After Danny falls into silence after seeing Miss Massey in the bathtub, she calls Dick Hallorann, who help

